<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gerko Vink</title>
    <link>https://gerkovink.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gerko Vink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 06:44:20 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gerkovink.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://gerkovink.github.io/abt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 06:44:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gerkovink.github.io/abt/</guid>
      <description>I am a statistical scientist with a passion for educating people. I aim to be at the cutting edge of both teaching and research and have an interest in new developments concerning the presentation of data, results and knowledge. I have a specific interest for incomplete data problems, optimisation and programming. I am based in the Netherlands and work as an assistant professor at Utrecht University (Utrecht, Netherlands).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bami is awesome!</title>
      <link>https://gerkovink.github.io/bami/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 06:44:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gerkovink.github.io/bami/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consultation</title>
      <link>https://gerkovink.github.io/cnslt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 06:44:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gerkovink.github.io/cnslt/</guid>
      <description>I advice, manage and supervise governments, companies and researchers on inference and causal estimation problems with incomplete data. I am always available for consultation: drop me a line and we&amp;rsquo;ll take it from there.
I have a broad experience as a consultant and have advised and trained government bodies, for-profit companies and institutions, NGOs, hospitals, universities and fellow researchers across the globe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses</title>
      <link>https://gerkovink.github.io/crs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 06:44:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gerkovink.github.io/crs/</guid>
      <description>I teach courses about multiple imputation and statistical programming in R to students, companies, statistical professionals and applied researchers. Most of these courses can be considered professional continuing education at a post-graduate level. If you would like to hire me for a private course, contact me for a quote.
I can highly recommend the courses I teach on R and Imputation in the Utrecht University Summerschool; you&amp;rsquo;ll get a comprehensive overview of the state of the art while keeping the course fees very affordable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development</title>
      <link>https://gerkovink.github.io/dvlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 06:44:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gerkovink.github.io/dvlp/</guid>
      <description>mice in R I actively develop for package mice in R.
 Mice is an awesome piece of multiple imputation software that allows you to generate multivariate imputations via Fully Conditional Specification (FCS) and Joint Modeling. Have a look at the mice Github and the mice vignettes.
 The mice package contains functions to:
 Inspect the missing data pattern Impute the missing data $m$ times, resulting in $m$ completed data sets Diagnose the quality of the imputed values Analyse each completed data set Pool the results of the repeated analyses Store and export the imputed data in various formats  to e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research activities</title>
      <link>https://gerkovink.github.io/pubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 06:44:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gerkovink.github.io/pubs/</guid>
      <description>Meet the research team:  Stef van Buuren [Full prof] Rianne Schouten [PhD Student] Mingyang Cai [PhD Student]  Selection of submitted/working papers  [with Jeroen Pannekoek and Stef van Buuren] Predictive ratio matching imputation of nested compositional data with semicontinuous variables. Towards a standardised evaluation of missing data methods. [with Yvonne Stikkelbroek and more] Effectiveness and moderators of individual Cognitive Behavioral Therapy (CBT) versus Treatment As Usual (TAU)in clinically depressed adolescents.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>